CURRICULAM-VITAE

ATUL KUMAR BHARADWAJ

1758 Janta Flats, G.T.B. Enclave, Dilshad Garden, Delhi 110093 Email Id: atulbhardwaj03@gmail.com

Contact Number: 9560215030, 9560485030

Profile Summary:

Diverse experience with a background in Information Technology, focusing on development on Java and Dot Net platforms. Over four years of experience in various aspects of Digital Marketing including Search Engine Optimization, Social Media Marketing, Pay Per Click. Future plans include to go deeper into Digital Marketing while working with established MNCs.

Education Qualification:

Master of Computer Application (M.C.A) - 2008 - 2011

Completed MCA from Krishna Engineering College, Ghaziabad affiliated to Gautam Buddha Technical University, Lucknow (Formally known as UPTU) with 1st div securing with 73% marks.

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A – Correspondence) – 2012 - 2014

Completed MBA from Punjab Technical University with 1st div securing 71% marks.

Bachelor of Computer Application (B.C.A) - 2005 to 2008

Completed BCA from IME (Institute of Management Education) affiliated to C.C.S. University Meerut (2005-2008) with 1st div securing with 70 % marks.

Professional Experience:

- 1. June 2013- Present: **KOENIG SOLUTIONS LTD,** New Delhi, India. Sr. Executive Google AdWords.
- 2. April 2012- May 2013: InvestInNest (Pioneer Media Line) Pvt. Ltd., Noida, UP. Executive Digital Marketing.
- **3.** February 2011 March 2012: **W3 Solutions**, New Delhi. Executive- Search Engine Optimization

Revenue Focused Marketing - Creating Strategy for the growth of the assigned Technology Domain - Generating Demand and Lead Generation through Google AdWords Search Ads, Bing Ads, Display Marketing on Google Display Network, Social Media - Facebook Ads, YouTube Ads & LinkedIn Ads, Twitter, Remarketing Campaigns for B2C Lead Generation (Retail) Offshore IT Training for our 5 centers in India (Delhi, Bangalore, Shimla, Goa & Dehradun), 1 Centre in Dubai and Live Virtual Classroom (Online Training) Mode. And B2B Lead Generation Onsite Trainings/Corporate Clients – Fly Me A Trainer Mode.

Primary Responsibilities

- Defining the Organization's Digital Marketing Goals with CEO and Group Managers.
 Coordination with Technical Managers, Sales Representatives, RTC Team (24x7 Real Time Chat), Web Designers & Developers to ensure the proper implementation of the Digital Marketing Strategy
- Planning, Creation & Implementation of the Digital Marketing Strategy & creating a Revenue Report every month by extracting Registration(Sales) Data from Microsoft Dynamics CRM & tracking growth of the assigned Technology Domain on monthly & quarterly basis (using 3 months moving average method) & accordingly proposing a marketing budget for the next month/quarter
- Search Engine Marketing (PPC) on Google AdWords/Bing Ads and Display Marketing on Google Display Network: Creation, Implementation & Management of Organization's PPC campaigns on Google AdWords & Bing Ads and Display Marketing Campaigns on Google Display Network across the Globe.
 - B2C Lead Generation Offshore IT Training for 1 Centre in Dubai, 5 Centers in India & Live
 Virtual Classroom (Online Training) Mode
 - o B2B Lead Generation Onsite Training/Corporate Clients Fly Me A Trainer Mode
 - Recruitment Campaigns Strategic implementation of Recruitment Campaigns on Google Search & Google Display Network for hiring new talent for current job openings at Koenig Solutions
 - Account Management Planning, Creation & Managing of Campaigns, Ad Groups, Ad copies and Keywords across various Search Platforms viz. Google Search & Bing Search and Banner Ads Campaigns on Google Display Network

- Display Marketing Planning, Creation & Managing Banner Ad Campaigns on Google Display Network
- Display Network Placement Research Researching for finding relevant Website
 Placements to be used as 'Managed Placement' in AdWords for showing Banners Ads. Tools used for this: Google Display Planner & Google Search
- Display Network Optimization Constantly monitoring Leads coming through Google
 Display Network & eliminating the website placements which are bringing junk leads.
- Keyword Research: Extensive Keyword Research using Google AdWords Keyword Planner Tool, Übersuggest & by analyzing Search Term Reports
- o Copywriting: Copywriting of Google Search Ads & Landing Page Content
- A/B Testing: Extensive Split Testing, A/B Testing of Ad Copies to achieve High Click Through Rates (CTR) & High Conversion Rates
- Landing Page Optimization (Multivariate Testing): Extensive A/B Testing, Multivariate
 Testing of various versions of Landing Pages for Conversion Centered Design to achieve High
 Conversion Rates
- Account Restructuring for Optimal Performance based on Relevancy & Themes Creation of Theme Based Campaigns & Ad Groups for various products/services, these tightly optimized theme-based campaigns/ad groups result in High Quality Scores (8+), thereby reducing the Cost Per Click (CPC), Cost Per Acquisition (CPA) and thus reducing the Overall Cost & Maximizing ROI
- o **RLSA Ads** Creating RLSA (Remarketing Lists for Search Ads) Campaigns retargeting website visitors on Google Search Network
- Remarketing Ads Creation of innovative remarketing strategies to retarget website visitors on Google Display Network. Having separate marketing funnels for converting & nonconverting website visitors
- Account Optimization Implementation of various Optimization Techniques to Increase Conversion Rates, Quality Scores, Click Through Rate (CTR) & Ad Rank. And Reducing Overall Cost by Reducing Cost Per Click (CPC) & Cost Per Acquisition (CPA)
- Maximizing Conversions, Client Acquisition, Sales and Lead Generation through strategic implementation of Industry Best Practices & Coming up with Innovative Solutions to Optimization Problems

- Monitoring Budget Spent, Avg. CPC, Conversion Rate & Cost Per Acquisition (CPA) on Daily, Weekly & Monthly Basis.
- Lead Tracking & Monitoring in CRM Tracking & Monitoring of the Lead Generated in Microsoft Dynamics CRM throughout the Sales Cycle till the Final Registration (Sale).
- Revenue Tracking By implementing AdWords Value Tracking & other tracking techniques, we track which keyword or website placement brought in the Final Registration(Sale) and we leverage this data in optimizing our Digital Marketing Campaigns for Maximum ROI
- Coordination with Global Technical Managers, Technical Managers, Sales Representatives in UK & US, International & Domestic Sales Teams in India, RTC Team (24x7 Real Time Chat), Web Designers & Developers to ensure the proper implementation of the Digital Marketing Strategy
- Social Media Marketing Creation, Implementation & Management of Organization's Social Media PPC Campaigns viz. Facebook Ads, YouTube Ads & LinkedIn Ads across the Globe
 - o **Facebook Ads** Running Facebook Ads using Facebook Power Editor Showing Ads on Newsfeed & Right Hand Column with the following marketing goals:
 - Lead Generation Campaigns targeting users based on interest, behaviour & demographics
 - Facebook Retargeting Campaigns retargeting our website visitors on Facebook
 - Like Campaigns Facebook Ads to increase Likes on Company's Facebook Page
 - Post Engagement Ads Promoting Posts published on Company's Facebook Page to increase engagement on the posts
 - To increase the no. of attendees for our frequently held Webinars
 - Moderating & replying to the comments in comments section of Facebook Ads. Have been able to do sales in Facebook comments itself by interacting with prospects
 - YouTube Ads Running YouTube Ads in In-stream, In-display & In-search Ad Formats with the following marketing goals:
 - Lead Generation Campaigns targeting specific YouTube Videos, Channels & Websites as placements and Targeting through Topic, Keyword, Interest & Demographics
 - YouTube Views Campaigns to increase the no. of views for a particular YouTube Video
 Like Campaigns Facebook Ads to increase Likes on Company's Facebook Page
 - Retargeting YouTube Video viewers & our website visitors on YouTube
 - o LinkedIn Ads Running LinkedIn Ads targeting specific groups for Lead Generation

- Google Analytics: Expertise in Google Analytics. Creation of required reports from GA:
 - o Creating Dashboards & Reports in Google Analytics.
 - Tracking Implementing techniques like URL Tagging & Value Tracking to track visitor's right to the keyword level.
 - Crucial Reports Creation of crucial reports like User Flow Reports, Audience Reports & Multi Channel Funnels Reports etc. Analysing these reports to gain critical insights & taking business decisions.
 - o **Behavioral Remarketing:** Creating Remarketing Lists in Google Analytics based on the behavior of the user.

Skills

- Pay Per Click Marketing through Google Adwords on Google Search Engine and Bing Ads on Bing Search
- **Display Marketing** Can create Banner Ad campaigns for Ecommerce Conversions & Lead Generation etc. on Google Display Network
- **Email Marketing:** Creating Email Lists of targeted prospects, maintaining a Great Relationship with the List, List Segmentation based on demographics and interests thus dividing a big Email List into smaller Laser Targeted Sub-Lists, and emailing relevant offers to the List
- Webinar Marketing Expertise in Planning, Execution & Promotion of Webinars using Cisco Webex
- Expertise in Tools: Google Adwords Keyword Planner, Adwords Display Planner, Adwords Editor, Google Analytics, Webmaster Tool.
- Competitor Analysis through AdWords Auction Insights & various Market Research Techniques.
- Strong project management skills, ability to work on multiple projects simultaneously and prioritize based on judgment
- Motivated Self-Starter with a Strong Desire to Learn New Methodologies of Internet Marketing

- Quick Learner
- Motivated Self Learner: Have the ability to learn any new skill from scratch
- Strong Analytical Ability
- Strong Problem Solving Ability: Can come up with innovative solutions to problems
- Excellent Verbal and Written Communication Skills
- Team-Player with Excellent Communication Skills

Certifications

- Google AdWords Certified Professional (Google Partner) Exams Cleared: Advertising Fundamentals, Advanced Search, Advanced Display, Video Advertising (Google Partner Profile URL: https://goo.gl/UDYMti)
- Google Analytics Certified Professional (Google Partner) Profile URL: https://goo.gl/gcQNYg

Extracurricular Activities

- Captained the College Volleyball team from 2005-2007, and lead the team to the Zonal Finals.
- Won the title on "Mr. Fresher" during the 1st year of college.
- Represented the college in sporting events (Volleyball, Table Tennis and Cricket) and won many awards.
- Active participant and organizer for most events throughout the calendar year at Koenig Solutions.
- Won the "Koenig Star" award for impressive performance during quarter.

Community Involvement

KOENIG KOSHISH: Volunteer to teach Mathematics, and Social Sciences to underprivileged children from grades 3-7 every alternate Friday, in the slums of Shalimar Bagh, New Delhi. (August 2014-Present)

Languages Spoken

English – Fluent (Understood, Read, and Spoken with Fluency)
Hindi – Fluent (Understood, Read, and Spoken with Fluency)
Punjabi – Fluent (Understood and Spoken with Fluency)

Declaration:

I solemnly declare that the facts stated above in the resume are correct and true to the best of my knowledge.